# Vivek Raja

.Net Full Stack Developer with a passion for software development with agile practices. With an in depth knowledge of .Net and JavaScript based frameworks and technologies.

A3B, XS Real Amity, OMR, Padur, Chennai - 603103 +91 7667 120495 king4vivek@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Over 6.5 years of experience in software development, spanning from ASP.NET to ASP.NET MVC using C# with team leadership and mentoring skills.

Has the ability to understand and transform complex business requirements into software, ensuring applications are delivered on time, to specification, are scalable, performance optimized and maintainable.

A highly motivated individual who is always learning, encourages learning, sharing of ideas and is always open to new ways of working.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Tata Consultancy Services,** Chennai — *Senior Developer*

Jan 2017 - Present

TCS is a top employer globally, and our 390,880+ employees represent 131 nationalities across 46 countries. As global leaders in IT services, digital, and business solutions, TCS partner with clients to simplify, strengthen, and transform their businesses.

# Plintron Global Technologies and Solutions Pvt. Ltd, Chennai — Senior Developer

Nov 2011 - Jan 2017

Plintron is a global player in Cloud Mobility Solutions and sports the telecom industry's most comprehensive rollouts for MNOs, MVNOs and Enterprises.

#### **EDUCATION**

Sun College of Engineering and Technology, Anna University, Tirunelveli — *Information Technology* 

Jun 2007 - Apr 2011

**Government Higher Secondary School, Chettikulam,** Tirunelveli — *HSC* [Computer Science]

Jun 2005 - Apr 2007

## **SKILLS**

# **Programming Language**

C#

# **Scripting Language**

JavaScript

# **Server Side Technologies**

ASP.Net MVC, WebApi, ADO.Net, LINQ, oAuth, Razor View

# **Client Side Technologies**

Angular, jQuery, TypeScript, Ajax, JSON, HTML, Bootstrap, CSS

#### **DBMS**

Microsoft SQL, Sybase SQL

#### **Version Control Tools**

Git, VSS

#### **Unit Testing Framework**

NUnit

### **IDE**

Microsoft Visual Studio SQL Server Management Studio Visual Studio Code

# **PROJECTS**

# American International Quality Underwriting and Information Capture 2.0 $-{\it AIG}$

Jan 2017 - Present

Senior Developer, Technical Lead

ASP.Net MVC WebApi, C#, Sybase SQL, Angular

AIQUIC is an underwriting application to serve a series of processes like Quote, negotiate, bind, issue and renew business faster than any other marketplace competitor. QUIC interfaces with various existing systems in the AIG systems environment, and supports DevOps pipeline.

# **Customer Relationship Management** — Lyca Mobile

Sep 2014 - Jan 2017

Senior Developer

ASP.Net MVC, C#, SQL Server, Angular JS, jQuery, Bootstrap CSS

CRM is a Single Page Application (SPA). It combines the functionalities of both CBOS and CPOS in rich and responsive user interface. Build from scratch using agile & scrum methodology. CRM developed using latest web technologies and designs for user friendly UI and fast response time. And supports DevOps.

### **Customer Point of Sale** — Lyca Mobile

Apr 2012 - Aug 2014

Developer

ASP.Net, C#, SQL Server, jQuery, CSS

Business operation like creating the Retailers, Cash on mobile features, Balance transfer, Card based Top-up, Reports generation, Dynamic allocation of Sims, are carried out by the CPOS Application and the support is provided for multiple countries, multiple brands and multiple language.

# **Customer Back Office System** — Lyca Mobile

Nov 2011 - Aug 2014

Developer

ASP.Net, C#, SQL Server, jQuery, CSS

Business support for mobile operations like Activation, Registration, of SIM and Vouchers, Top-up services, Bundle Subscription, Mobile number portability, Brand affiliation, SIM swap, Re credit features and all telecom related operation are carried out by CBOS.

#### **PERSONAL**

#### **Date of Birth**

10 September 1989

#### Gender

Male

#### **Marital Status**

Married

### Father's name

Thangaraja

#### **Permanent Address**

5/150-A, Sathyapuram Road, Chettikulam, Tirunelyeli – 627120

#### **Hobbies**

Wiki, News, Sports

# Languages

Tamil, English

### **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

T VIVEK RAJA